Ian Baumeister (preferred name) Ian Buimistr (legal name)

Contact

Address: 10178 Berlin Mitte, Germany

GitHub: Phone: +4917636127937 http://github.com/ibxibx ian@ianworks.dev Email: Website: http://ianworks.dev

Linkedin:

http://linkedin.com/in/avoiann/

Citizenship: German

Summary Junior Full Stack Web Developer with a strong foundation in coding and a passion for problem solving and exploring cutting-edge frameworks. Posessing a solid background in graphic / UX / UI design and business / startup development. Has delivered design solutions, improved web presence and increased sales. Has acquired skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, Angular and brings a unique perspective to building user-centric, innovative and impactful products and services. Looking to join a forward-thinking company that impacts people's everyday lives and creates abundance.

Web Development Projects

NextChat - A React Native App - Oct 2024 - Course Project https://github.com/ibxibx/nextchat https://bit.ly/iannextchat

Built a feature-rich mobile chat application from the ground up using React Native and Expo (for both Android and iOS) allowing users to easily communicate via text messages, images, and location sharing. Built and a user-friendly design interface with Gifted Chat, set up the Google Firebase/Firestore for anonymous authentication, message and media storage and integrated it into the app. Coded all the photo and location functions in the CustomActions component, offline and online data storage in the Chat component. Launched, tested and debugged the app with Android Studio to make sure all functions worked smoothly. Berlin, Germany

MyMDB - My Movie Database (Server Side and Client Side) - Jun / Jul 2024 - Course Project https://github.com/ibxibx/mymdb https://mymdb-app.netlify.app/login

Coded the complete server-side and client-side for a web application from scratch. Using the MERN Stack - created a RESTful API which interacts with a custom non-relational database (MongoDB), and tested API endpoints in Postman. Built the interface of a single-page responsive application; developed with React, resulting in a fully functional web-app allowing users to register and login, view their favourite movies and their details, and update their user profile and credentials. Used Bootstrap for styling and responsiveness, Launched and tested, debugged both the server and client side until flawless application performance was achieved.

Berlin, Germany

Work Experience

Nov 2021 - Aug 2023, Dec 2023 - Mar 2024

lan Baumeister / Self-employed - ianbaumeister.wordpress.com http://behance.net/ianbau

Freelance Graphic, Media Designer | Project and Business Developer.

SEO / Website and Product Management and Marketing.

Focused on the self-employed and small businesses who need help with their website and web presence. Provided digital and print design solutions and consulted over 100 customers, helping them increase conversions and sales, optimise their web and social media presence, enabling them to increase website user engagement by up to +40% and / or sales by up to +30%.

Berlin / Hamburg, Germany

Sep - Nov 2023

Smartments Business / GBI - smartments-business.de

Junior Sales Manager - Rental of Serviced Apartments in Germany & Austria. Worked from 3 Cities and 5 Apart-Hotels. Helped manage and maintain 40+ corporate and private customer (new and existing) inquiries, taken care of 200+ customer database records, drafted and curated contract delivery, facilitated daily customer care.

Berlin / Hamburg / Mannheim, Germany

Dec 2019 - Oct 2021

DiamondSite - Website and App Development and Maintanance Service.

Head of Design and Marketing, Startup Co-Founder.

Identified a huge gap in the diversified & growing market. Created a compelling offer. Designed and structured the product-service. Optimised 50+ websites / blogs / social media channels.

Berlin, Germany

Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

DiamondClose - Online Coaching Service for Young Professionals.

Head of Design and Marketing, Startup Co-Founder.

Discovered a big need in the freelancing market for upscaling services and finding high ticket clients. Iterated and created coaching packages, trained and advised 40 (combined) young professionals on how to more effectively market and sell their services as freelance programmers and designers. Berlin, Germany

Apr 2014 - Sep 2018

AvoTravel part of AVO Group - Online Marketplace for Business-Fit Rental Real Estate.

Head of Design and Marketing, Product Manager, Startup Co-Founder.

Observed an emerging sharing economy trend and a massive market opportunity, worked in international teams, organised the work-flow and KPIs, drafted and designed the marketplace and concierge service products, closed partnerships with 36 real estate management companies, facilitated rental contracts with full proof of concept execution (€17,000), pitched to investors. expanded the real estate portfolio listing over 1200 Units in 6 countries.

Berlin, Germany / San Francisco, Silicon Valley, USA

Skills / Knowledge

Web Development Skills / Front End & Back End

Creating websites from the ground up, JavaScript, Node.is, Express, Angular, React.js, TypeScript, HTML, CSS / SCSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Google Material Design, JQuery, Mongoose, Data Storage with AWS, AJAX, Google Firestore, Serverless, MySQL, Agile Development, Kanban, Jira, Trello, Coding, Troubleshooting, Debugging, Problem Solving, Unit Testing (Jest), End-to-End Testing (Puppeteer), Integration Testing (Cucumber), Behaviour-driven Development (Gherkin), Postman (Testing), Building mobile Apps with React Native and Expo. API. RESTful. JSON. JWT Authentication and Authorization with Password Middleware, Relational & Non-Relational Databases (Mongo DB, PostgreSQL), Visual Studio Code, GitHub. PowerShell. Command Prompt.

Additional Skills / Software

Graphic Design (Web/Print), Interior Design, Product Design, Media Design (Video Editing), Service Design, Management, Lean Development, Creative Thinking, Business Strategy, Online & Offline Marketing, SEO, Client Acquisition, Strategy, Presentation & Social Skills, Public Speaking, Team Leading, Organisational Talent, Product and Project Management.

Al: ChatGPT, Claude.ai, Google Gemini, Midjourney Office Suite: Outlook, Word, Excell, Acrobat, PowerPoint **Graphics:** Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Figma, Autodesk AutoCAD LT, Adobe Dreamweaver, Adobe InDesign, Al Blockadelabs.

Sound Editing: Cool Edit Pro. Video Editing: Wondershare Filmora.

CRM: Apaleo, Pipedrive, Citrix, Bitrix24, Mailchimp.

Languages

Fluent: English, German, Romanian, Russian, Czech

Education

Apr 2024 - Nov 2024

areerFoundry.com - Full Stack Web Development Course Degree: Full Stack Web Developer

Berlin, Germany / Remote

Apr - May 2014

ounder Institute - Fi.co

Startup Founding, Product Service Validation, Development, Expansion, Marketing, Management, Business Strategy, Customer Acquisition.

Berlin, Germany / Palo Alto, USA - Hybrid

2014 - 2017

Hackathon Competitions - BattleHack, EcomHack etc. Built and Prototyped Innovative Online Product-Services, Worked in dynamic teams and in tight schedules, created product features, designed presentations & app interfaces, pitched the final product demos. Distinguished Projects:

"BrAvo" - 3rd Place - at ImmobilienScout24 "Angel Pro" - Special Prize - at Ebay, PayPal Berlin, Germany / London, UK

2003 - Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA) Degree

Interests / Hobbies

Technology, Travel, Video & Media, DJ-ing, Sport & Fitness, Architecture.